Parth Shah

7, Sunita Apartment, Near Gayatri Hospital, , Kiranpark, New Wadaj, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India 380013 Contact No: (+91)9727828412 Email ID: parth.shah14786@gmail.com Skype ID: parth.shah14786

Objective

Qualified IT Professional with dedication, proactive approach, positive attitude and passion towards the work that will fully utilize logical and reasoning abilities in the best possible way for the fulfillment of personal and organizational goals.

Education

B.Tech, Information Technology

2008

Ganpat University, Gujarat, India - First Class

Technical Skills

- ‡ Scripting Languages: PHP, HTML5, CSS, Ajax, JQuery, AngularJS, Core Java, XML
- ‡ Tools & IDE: Eclipse, Android Studio, Android SDK, XAMPP, WampServer
- ‡ Operating Systems: Windows 7, Ubuntu
- ‡ Databases: MySQL, SQLite
- ‡ Hosting Servers: Manashosting, ZnetLive, Google Play Store
- ‡ Payment Gateways: Paypal, Authorize.net, CCAvenue
- ‡ Office Tools: MS Office, LibreOffice, Apache OpenOffice

Learning & Implementation: PHP, HTML5, Ajax, CSS, JQuery, AngularJS, Restful API, Web Services, Payment Gateways, Codelgniter (MVC), Core Java, XML, JSON, Android Development, Google AdMob, In-App Purchase, API Push Notification, Technical Documentation, Social Media, Managing and Hosting Live Websites, Online Communities

Work Experience	
Value Chain Solutions Ltd., Ahmedabad, India Software Developer	2008 to 2009
* Application Development & Technical Documentation	
IT Freelancer (PHP & Android), Ahmedabad, India Entrepreneur	2010 to 2016
* IT Consulting, Application Development & Technical Documentation	
Rubikube Solutions Ltd, Pune, India Application Developer	2010 to 2012
* Application Development, E-Learning, Six Sigma etc.	
Suvidhi Financial Services Ltd, Ahmedabad, India Senior Android Developer	2012 to Present

Oxylabs Consulting Services Ltd, Ahmedabad, India Senior IT Consultant (Web & Mobile Development)

* Application Development, Financial Consulting, & Software Maintenance

2016 to Present

* Android Development, PHP Development, Code Review, Debugging, Manual Testing, Client Communication & Agile Methodology

Professional Projects

Project 1: Online Showroom

Project Type: Web Application Tools & IDE: Eclipse, PHPMyAdmin Technology Used: Core Java, HTML5, JSP

Database: MySQL

Organization: Argusoft India Ltd.

Description: I have made this Project for my Internship Training at Argusoft India Ltd. There are two modules and working independently. User can register, Login and view the latest showroom products with the price. I have submitted this project within the timeline.

Project 2: C-Logix

Project Type: Web Application

Tools & IDE: Visual Studio 2008, SQL Server 2000 Technology Used: Asp.net, C#, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript

Database: MSSQL, MS Excel

Organization: Value Chain Solutions Pvt Ltd.

Description: I have create database design for this project in MSSQL. I've made GUI pages in .aspx extension for the project. As per the client requirement I've created Class files in C# language as well as changes in relevant databases.

Project 3: E-Cubix

Project Type: Web Application Technology Used: Asp.net, C# Database: MSSQL, MS Excel

Organization: Value Chain Solutions Pvt Ltd.

Description: I have create database design for this project in MSSQL. I've created Technical Documentation for this project [e.g. GUI Screenshot, Changes in User Guide etc.]. More over I've handled client queries through emails and calls for the project.

Project 4: Email Capture Utility

Project Type: Desktop Application

Technology Used: Eclise, Core Java, Swing

Database: SQLite

Organization: Suvidhi Financial Services Ltd.

Description: This utility help user to capture emails from the given URL and then save it to text file. I have Converted C# Code to Java Swing code for this Project. I have made this Cross Platform Desktop application for Financial Organization and support to managing director.

Project 5: Money4Future

Project Type: Web Application

Technology Used: PHP, HTML5, Ajax, CSS, jQuery etc.

Database: MySQL

Organization: Suvidhi Financial Services Ltd.

Description: Money4Future is a Finance Portal which includes basic facilities [e.g. Admin, Record Database, Customer Information, Authentication]. I have made this Sample Web Application for Financial Organization and support to managing director.

Project 6: Medical Store Management

Project Type: Desktop Application Tools & IDE: Eclipse, SQLite Studio

Technology Used: Core Java, JDK, Java Swing

Database: SQLite

Organization: Sr. IT Consultant @Entrepreneur

Description: This utility is helpful to healthcare professional. It has all the facilities to manage medicine list. User Can login into the system using appropriate credentials. User can see the list of available medicines, add new medicine, delete old one. User can have login facility as well as sign up facility for the module. It has simple use interface as well as front end design. I have made this application for my own learning and implementation purpose.

Project 7: Payment Reminder

Project Type: Mobile Application Tools & IDE: Eclipse, Android Studio

Technology Used: Core Java, XML, Android SDK

Database: SQLite

Organization: Suvidhi Financial Services Ltd.

Description: Payment Reminder is a Financial Mobile Application. This Application includes all the basic facilities. [e.g. Customer Information, Loan Reminder, Check / Cash Reminder, , Generate Password, Authentication etc]. It will automatically send alert to the registered email id. I have made this Mobile Application for Financial Organization and support to managing director.

Project 8: BillShare-Utility

Project Type: Mobile Application Tools & IDE: Eclipse, Android Studio

Technology Used: Core Java, XML, Android SDK

Database: SQLite

Organization: Sr. IT Consultant @Entrepreneur

Play Store: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.utility.billshare

Description: BillShare-Utility is an Android application which allows the user to calculate monthly bills, Share bills. Add Members as well as remind bills. User can add members to the list. User can see the different bills in customizable listview and select the appropriate item. User can see the pending bills as well as pending money for the particular bill. It has simple user interface as well as front end design. I have made this application for my own learning and implementation purpose.

Project 9: AdvancedCalc - Master

Project Type: Mobile Application Tools & IDE: Eclipse, Android Studio

Technology Used: Core Java, XML, Android SDK

Database: SQLite

Organization: Suvidhi Financial Services Ltd

Play Store: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.util.advancedcalc

Description: AdvancedCalc - Master is an Android application which allows user to do mathematical operations like addition, subtraction, multiplication and division. It has advanced scientific functions too. It will save user time and energy. It has simple user interface as well as nice front end screen. I have made this application for financial organisation and support to managing director.

Project 10: Loan Calculater - Master

Project Type: Mobile Application Tools & IDE: Eclipse, Android Studio

Technology Used: Core Java, XML, Android SDK etc.

Database: SQLite

Organization: Suvidhi Flnancial Services Ltd

Description: Local-Calc is a Moile Application. With the help of this application, customer can calculate the loan for a period of time. Customer can see the additional information about the respective loan. Customer can get alert messages for specific period of time. It has simple user interface as well as front end design. I have made this project for financial organisation and support to managing director.

Project 11: ContactBook

Project Type: Web Application

Tools & IDE: Eclipse, XAMPP, PHPMyAdmin

Technology Used: PHP, HTML5, Ajax, CSS, jQuery etc.

Database: MySQL

Organization: Sr. IT Consultant @Entrepreneur

Description: Contact Book is a Web Application based on PHP MVC architecture. User can add / update / delet contact using this portal. User can backup all the important contacts using this. User can save contacts on Hosting Server with appropriate login details. It has simple user interface as well as front end design. This Application is useful for individual Bachelor and/or Educational Institutes.

Project 12: DailyRoutine - Master

Project Type: Mobile Application Tools & IDE: Eclipse, Android Studio

Technology Used: Core Java, XML, Android SDK

Database: SQLite

Organization: Sr. IT Consultant @Entrepreneur

Play Store: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.utility.dailyroutine

Description: DailyRoutine utility helps user to quick remind the task at the given Date and Time. User can Add New Task, View All Task and Delete appropriate task. User can manage this app in Mobile and/or Tablet. User can see the history of the task and delete them too as per the requirement. It has simple user interface as well as front end design. I have made this application for my own learning and implementation purpose.

Project 13: StudentCourseGuide - Master

Project Type: Mobile Application Tools & IDE: Eclipse, Android Studio

Technology Used: Core Java, XML, Android SDK

Database: SQLite

Organization: Sr. IT Consultant @Entrepreneur

Play Store: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.edu.studentcourseguide

Description: StudentCourseGuide - Master is an educational application. It has sever features like Attendance, Event Notifier and CGPA. It can be useful to educational institutes as well as individual group. It will save user time and energy. User can see the Event Notifier in Google Calendar too and fix it direct from there. It has simple user interface as well as front end design I have made this application for my own learning and implementation purpose.

Project 14: EWatt - Master

Project Type: Mobile Application Tools & IDE: Eclipse, Android Studio

Technology Used: Core Java, XML, Android SDK

Database: SQLite

Organization: Sr. IT Consultant @Entrepreneur

Play Store: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.utility.ewatt

Description: EWatt - Master is an utility android application. This App is used to calculate estimate power consumption in house. It has many features like Estimate Consumption, Take Quiz, Power Saving Tips, Important Links. User can see the useful website link of Gujarat Electricity board on last screen. I have made this application for my own learning and implementation purpose.

Project 15: Online Library Catalog

Project Type: Web Application Tools & IDE: Eclipse, Android Studio

Technology Used: PHP, HTML5, Ajax, CSS, jQuery etc.

Database: MySQL

Organization: Sr. IT Consultant @Entrepreneur

Description: Online Library Catalog System is an library portal for university. There are two independent modules 1. admin and 2. user. Admin can handle the portal. User can add new books, view books as well search for the particular book using different criterias. User can have two facilities login and registration in this modules. First user can register himself with this and then login with the credentials. I have made this project for my own learning and implementation purpose.

Project 16: Virid Directory

Project Type: Mobile Application Tools & IDE: Eclipse, Android Studio

Technology Used: Core Java, XML, Android SDK

Database: SQLite

Organization: Suvidhi Financial Services Ltd

Play Store: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.utility.ViridDirectory

Description: Virid Directory is a perfect example android, sqlite crud example. User can add information, search information, view information and at the end delete the information too. User can see the sqlite data in customized listview. I have made this project for financial organisation and support to managing director.

Project 17: WebCrawler - Master

Project Type: Mobile Application
Tools & IDE: Eclipse. Android Studio

Technology Used: Core Java, XML, Android SDK

Database: SQLite

Organization: Sr. IT Consultant @Entrepreneur

Play Store: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=net.utility.webcrawler

Description: This is an android application which does web crawl for hyperlinks. The app stops crawling when 1000 links are gathered without user intervention. The UI button element which is labelled "Begin" if crawling not in progress else "Stop" to force stop crawling before 1000 links are gathered. Application utilizes up to 10 threads for crawling. It is capable of crawling gzip encoded pages and supports https connection. I have made this project for my own learning and implemmentation purpose.

Independent Coursework

Core Java (Programming Language) Laravel (MVC Framework) WordPress (Content Management System) Android OS (Mobile Operating System)

Key Highlights

Good Communication Skills, Team Player, Ready to Help, Good Listener & Observing things from root level

Hobbies and Interests

Listening Music, Programming, Surfing, Reading, Playing, Professional Networking and Innovation

Travel Experience

Bangalore, India (Duration: 3 Months)
Pune, India (Duration: 18 Months)
Singapore, Asia (Duration: 3 Days)

Visa Status

Singapore, Asia (24 Months Visitor Visa)

Malaysia, Asia (3 Months Visitor Visa)

Thailand, Asia (3 Months Visitor Visa)

Additional Information

Over 8+ Years of Experience in Web and Mobile Application Development. Currently I'm seeking for job change as a Senior Android Developer in Full Time / Part Time position. In addition, I'm looking for International Business Opportunity as per my skills and expertise. I can join your Organization / Technical Team as soon as possible. Let me know your criteria.

Professional References

Available upon request

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 14th July 1986

Languages Known: English, Hindi and Gujarati

Marital Status: Single Nationality: Indian

Preferred Location: As per the requirement